# Ryan Christian Fernandez

Ryan.Christian127@outlook.com (214) 731-7379 Markleville, IN

Driven with the passion to grow, I strive for quality while getting the job done and seek to achieve no less in my pursuit towards a career in the development world. With mounting experience in military, private, and public work sectors, my well-rounded skills aide in my goals to become the best me I can be.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Certifications: NCO Leadership Course [Aug. 10, 2018], Codecademy: CMD Line Bash [Jan. 27], Codecademy: Git [Feb. 3], Codecademy: GitHub [Feb. 7], Codecademy: SCRUM [Feb. 9], Codecademy: HTML [Feb. 11], Codecademy: CSS [Feb. 17]
- Skills: Project Management, HTML, CSS, Git, Bash, GitHub, Troubleshooting, Teamwork

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Generations Frontend Web Development Course

Jan. 2022 – Apr. 2022

Student (Cohort)

New Orleans, LA

- Participated in coursework covering theory to practical application in synchronous group environments.
  - o Built and developed 12 different websites using HTML and CSS.
  - o Ran professional growth scenarios and aided in the development of professional behavioral skills and mindsets.

**Marine Corps** 

Sep. 2014 – Sep. 2019

## Electronics/Optics Technician

Okinawa, Japan/Camp Lejeune, NC

- Under limited supervision, performed various duties to ensure fluid workflow in maintenance pipeline.
  - o Inventory and database management, logs and records upkeep, and retaining sensitive documentation.
- Supervisory position overseeing training of both new and existing domestic/international personnel.
  - o Individual counseling as well as large scale presentations covering groups between 5-50 individuals.

### Maintenance Technician and Quality Control

Sep. 2015 – Sep. 2017

- Maintained 4,000+ electro-mechanical equipment in isolation and in team-oriented environments
- Acting Quality Control on intermediate-advanced maintenance routines.

# **Assistant Logistics Operations Manager**

Sep. 2017 – Sep. 2019

- Acted as Assistant Logistics Manager while maintaining technician role.
  - o Tool and data control, managing physical and intellectual assets employing physical and digital controls
  - o Performed calibrations, library (digital/physical) management.

## Raytheon Intelligence & Space

Apr. 2021 – Jul. 2021

Production Associate (Contract)

McKinney, TX

- Intermediate Repairs on advanced targeting systems within ISO Class 5 Cleanroom Environment.
- Worked under direct supervision and performing rework tasks.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Ordnance School** 

Aug. 18, 2015

Electro-Optical Ordnance Repairer

Fort Lee, VA

Communication-Electronics Maintenance School

Jan. 5 - Mar. 24, 2017

Micro-Miniature Repair Course

Twentynine Palms, CA

Frontend Web Development

Jan. 18 - Apr. 14, 2022

Junior Web Developer Program

New Orleans, LA